<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on ATM4110</title>
    <link>https://hajsong.github.io/ATM4110/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on ATM4110</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 12:36:51 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hajsong.github.io/ATM4110/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Computing Environment</title>
      <link>https://hajsong.github.io/ATM4110/environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 12:36:51 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hajsong.github.io/ATM4110/environment/</guid>
      <description>The main tools being used in this course is Python and Jupyter Notebook.
Why are we going to learn python in this course? The scope of this class is to read atmospheric and oceanic datasets, do spatial, temporal and spectral analysis, and present the data graphically. Python provides an environment for us to fulfill those tasks seamlessly without asking too much time and effort to pay. Also, learning Python may open up other possibilities in your future because it is very popular computer languages these days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python</title>
      <link>https://hajsong.github.io/ATM4110/python/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 12:36:51 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hajsong.github.io/ATM4110/python/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python</title>
      <link>https://hajsong.github.io/ATM4110/environment/python/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 12:36:51 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hajsong.github.io/ATM4110/environment/python/</guid>
      <description>I refer to Unidata online python training page for this page.  I recommend you to visit Unidata Online Python Training page. The main program language we will use in this course to handle atmospheric data is python. Before getting into &amp;ldquo;What is Python?&amp;rdquo;, here is one of the statements that shows why we want to learn it
  I have used a combination of Perl, Fortran, NCL, Matlab, R and others for routine research, but found out this general- purpose language, Python, can handle almost all in an efficient way from requesting data from remote online sites to statistics, and graphics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>